# Alex Bruce

# **Computer Science**

6/6 West Preston Street Edinburgh EH8 9PX

+447548108737

<u>alexbruce225@gmail.com</u> www.github.com/alexic0n

#### Skills

Programming Languages: Java, Python, C, C++, Kotlin, SQL, Haskell and BASH.

Passion for cyber-security, focussed on studying cryptography and usable security throughout university.

Experience working with networks, from web hosting to running the AI Brain for a chess robot on a remote server communicating with a Raspberry Pi.

Knowledge of OS's and low level programming (experience using MIPs)

Can speak basic German, studying for A2 exam this year.

## **Experience**

#### **University of Edinburgh/** Summer Intern (IT Faculty)

May 2019 - July 2019

I worked for 8 weeks with the universities computer admin department. Responsibilities included deployment of new software and hardware, communicating changes with customers and fixing issues as they arose. A lot of the work was very independent and involved fixing problems in the network as they arose, often from remote locations.

This job also required high privileges on sensitive network, allowing me to experience the kind of issues that sys admins may face on a daily basis.

#### JD Wetherspoon/ Bar Associate

June 2017- September 2017

Working in a very tight knit team through a very stressful period of the year was very beneficial for me. I learned a lot about how to deal with interpersonal issues within the team and with customers.

## **Education**

#### **University of Edinburgh / Computer Science BSc**

September 2016 - June 2020

I've been studying for my bachelors at Edinburgh, with a focus on computer security. I'm currently averaging 75% in exams (across 3rd year) and am predicted to graduate with 1st in June 2020.

My dissertation focuses on Databases, and the advantages of relational systems.